Austin Wiley

Email: austin@spangalangbrewery.com | Phone: 303-905-7293 | Littleton, CO 80120

Github: https://github.com/AustinWiley

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/austin-wiley-86868416b/
Portfolio: https://austinwiley.github.io/Austin-Portfolio/

Web Developer and Entrepreneur. Experienced in creative problem solving, collaboration, team management, training and organization, product/process development and supply relations. Enjoys working in teams, whether that be in a position of leadership or taking instruction. A lifelong learner who taught myself how to start and run a successful business and now the endless possibilities of web development. Thanks to my years of working in cross-functional teams and running my own business, I'm great at coming up with solutions, no matter what you throw at me.

Technical Skills: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React Js, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars Js, Moment.js, NPM, Google Fonts, & Font Awesome, PHP, Laravel.

APPLICATIONS BUILT

BeerKan Github / Live

- Beer tracking app for the professional brewer and the avid homebrewer that works like a Kanban Board. BeerKan as a digital Brew log allowing the user to track each batch of beer from raw ingredient to keg. Allows the brewer to be more efficient, brew more beer and archive all brewlogs.
- Tools/Languages used: ES6, CSS5, React Js, Materialize, Heroku, Express, Handlebars, MySQL & Sequelize-ORM.

Burger-Sequelize Github / Heroku/ Live

- A Node, Express, Handlebars, and MySQL burger app that lets users input the names of burgers they'd like to eat... and then devour them!
- Tools/Languages used: Javascript, JQuery, Node.js, Heroku, Express, Twitter Bootstrap Handlebars, MySQL & Sequelize-ORM.

React Clicky Game Github / Heroku/Live

- Memory Game where the player clicks on images and tries not to click the same image twice. The images are reshuffled dynamically with each click using React
- Tools/Languages used: ES6, CSS5, React Js.

Camp With Confidence Github / Live

- Web app that searches National Park API for camp sites, takes in your camp site selection and returns weather forecast from Open Weather API for that location and uses Leaflet map API to show you a map location of the camp site.
- Tools/Languages used: Javascript, JQuery, Css, Google Firebase, Font Awesome, Twitter Bootstrap & Leaflet maps.

Liribot-node-app Github / Live

- LIRI is like iPhone's SIRI. However, while SIRI is a Speech Interpretation and Recognition Interface, LIRI is a Language Interpretation and Recognition Interface. LIRI is a node app that takes in parameters and gives you back data. LIRI will search Spotify API for songs, Bands in Town API for concerts, and OMDB API for movies.
- Tools/Languages used: Javascript, Node.js, Axios, Doteny, Moment.js.

Train Scheduler Github / Live

- One page Web App that allows you to create a Train Schedule with form input validation and persistent data using Google Firebase.
- Tools/Languages used: Javascript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Google Firebase and Moment.js.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Spangalang Brewery, Denver, CO

February 2015 - Present

Owner

Co-Founded and Operated a successful craft brewery. Created world class beer that won GABF Gold medal and World Beer Cup awards. Managed staff and daily operations of of the business including head of Human Resources. As Co-Founder, researched local and federal laws and regulations, obtained necessary permits and licenses and managed cross-functional communication between equipment Engineers, Architects, Contractors, and local government.

Denver Beer Co, Denver, CO

February 2014 - February 2015

Head Brewer

Managed Brew house operations and staff during a time of major growth. Developed and Brewed beer that became a major part of the companies portfolio as well as won nationally recognized awards and medals.

Great Divide Brewing Co, Denver, CO

April 2007 - February 2014

Lead Brewer

Research and recipe development for award winning beer, team management, staff training, equipment accusation and creating production processes and standards playing a major role in helping the company increase production during a time of rapid growth.

EDUCATION

University of Denver, Denver, CO

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars JS, & React Js, PHP, Laravel.